welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it federalism an idea that combines
a general government with regional
governments in a single political system
the Articles of Confederation was the
original attt at being a federalist
document the issue is is that it didn't
maintain a balance between states and
the federal government and gave states
too much power and this ended up making
the documents being weak state
representatives all knew this and
decided to meet in 1787 at the
Constitutional Convention where they
would through negotiation collaboration
and compromise draft a new form of
government being the con which made a
more central government the actual
details of the Constitution will be
covered next topic for now let's talk
about this convention the idea of
federalism changed as a result of this
convention the way it changed was
articulated in a document known as The
Federalist Papers written by Hamilton
and Madison arguing a strong central
government was necessary to create a
perfect union and to protect the
individual liberties of the people so
basically it was condemning the articles
that did not achieve this central
government then a new group would pop up
opposing this imposition of the new
constitution known as the
Anti-Federalist people in this
anti-federalist group like Patrick Henry
and George Mason argued that the
constitution didn't address States and
individual rights enough because of this
to ensure the Constitution would be
ratified Federalists promised the
addition of the Bill of Rights which
were the first 10 amendments to the
United States they emphasized individual
rights and explicitly restricted the
powers of the federal government to
appease the Anti-Federalist groups the
best way to describe the Constitution is
Ben Franklin's speech at the convention
where he said he didn't approve of parts
of the Constitution but acknowledged
that a perfect document would be
impossible and this was likely the best
thing that could be made however there
was always one big issue and from now
until 1865 slavery will be that issue
the Constitutional Convention
compromised on slavery by doing two
things first they would pledge that
Congress could not prohibit the
international slave trade until 1808
second they made it so enslaved people
would count as 3 fifths of a person when
calculating a state's population for
representation in Congress hence it was
known as the 3- fifths compromise but
understand that even though slavery was
such a glaring issue know that the word
slavery was actually never mentioned in
the Constitution and that's all for this
one on the screen now are AP style
questions for this topic pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
now see you in the next one